Welcome to our training on virtual bundles.
Amazon customers often shop for multiple items at once and use brands to help identify products
that go together.
A flower pot and a pack of seeds, for example, or shampoo and conditioner.
To make it easier for customers to find and purchase related products, we created the Virtual Bundles
program.
A virtual bundle is a group of two to five products on a single product detail page.
The individual products are all part of the same brand and are available on their own product detail
pages too.
But the virtual bundle allows customers to purchase them as a group.
Let's find out how brands create virtual bundles.
Before we review the process, let's go over a few key requirements and conditions.
There are two basic requirements for all virtual bundles.
The first is that the products they contain need to be part of a brand enrolled in Amazon brand
registry.
The seller who creates a bundle needs to be internal to the brand too.
If you'd like more information about brand registry and access to brand selling benefits like virtual
bundles,
see the series of modules in our Seller University course, launch your brand in the Amazon store.
The second basic requirement for virtual bundles is that the products they contain need to be shipped
through fulfillment by Amazon or FBA.
The seller who creates the bundle also needs to have an FBA account in good standing.
Your FBA products must be in new condition too, and they can't be a gift card or an electronically
delivered item like digital music, a video or an e-book.
When a customer orders a virtual bundle through FBA, each item is fulfilled separately, just like
for a standard order.
We don't charge additional FBA or selling fees.
Sellers don't have to package products together or make any other changes to their inventory either.
The quantity of virtual bundles you have in stock is determined by the smallest quantity available
for an individual product in the bundle.
For example, if you sell a bundle that contains a dart board and a set of 5 darts, and you have
10 dart boards and 15 sets of darts in stock,
you'll have 10 virtual bundles available.
All 25 of your products will still be stored separately in our fulfillment centers and available
for individual purchase too.
When a customer buys one of your 10 dart boards, you'll have 9 dart boards and 9 virtual bundles
left in stock.
And when another customer buys your bundle, you'll have 8 bundles, 8 dart boards, and 14 sets of
darts left.
In addition to the requirements for brand registry and FBA, virtual bundles need to meet a few conditions.
First, they need to be organized around a main product.
We use this main product to drive searches for your virtual bundle, which means its keywords become
the bundle's keywords.
Other attributes from the main product, like category, are also carried over to your bundle.
The same main product can be used to create multiple virtual bundles.
For example, a t-shirt could be bundled 4 times with 4 different pairs of pants from your brand.
But make sure you don't create bundles that contain the same group of products with a different
main product assigned.
Don't create a bundle with a t-shirt as a main product, and pants as another product, then create
a second bundle with the same two items
that uses the pants as the main product.
It's also important to note that sellers can't create virtual bundles as variations.
If you want to create bundles that contain different versions of a product, for color or size, for
example,
create a separate bundle for each version rather than trying to establish variation relationships.
In addition, each virtual bundle you create needs to contain two to five different products within
your brand.
A virtual bundle can't be a group of the same product, like a multi-pack, case pack, or pallet.
Virtual bundles can contain multiple units of a single product in combination with other products.
For example, a virtual bundle could contain two of the same coffee mugs, as long as it also included
other products like a bag of coffee and a coffee pot.
It's important to note, however, that you can't have multiple units of a main product in a virtual
bundle.
In our example, either the bag of coffee or the coffee pot could be the main product, but the two
mugs couldn't.
Make sure the products you include in a bundle are also complementary and compatible.
Group products that are used together.
And if you're bundling products like a phone and charging cable, make sure they're designed to be
used together.
The last condition for a virtual bundle is that its price needs to be either the same as the total
price for the products in the bundle,
or lower if you'd like to offer customers a discount for purchasing multiple items at once.
Remember that reduced prices can help attract customers.
If the price of an individual product in your virtual bundle decreases, make sure that the price
of the bundle is still equal to or lower than the combined price for all the products in it.
Bundle prices don't update automatically in response to updates in the prices of individual products.
So make sure you check your bundle prices when you update individual products.
Or set pricing rules that keep virtual bundle prices at or below the combined price for bundled
products.
Note too that a bundle that's priced higher than the sum of its product prices can't become a featured
offer in the Amazon store.
Now that you know requirements and conditions for virtual bundles, let's learn how to create one.
All sellers who meet the requirements for virtual bundles can access the tool by hovering over brands
in the main menu,
clicking Build Your Brand, then scrolling down and locating the virtual bundles card.
On the new virtual bundle page, you'll start by selecting two to five products.
Click the Add Products button, then in the pop-up, browse for products or enter one asin at a time
in the search bar.
Click Add to Bundle at the end of a row to make it part of the bundle.
The product you add first will be set as your bundle's main product.
When you're finished adding products, click the Done Adding Products button to return to the new
virtual bundle page with your products populated.
Next, underneath your bundle's product list, click Select Images and Layout to go to a second pop-
up where you'll upload a main image for your bundle and select Additional Product Images.
For your main image, click the Browse button to upload a new image that shows each product in your
bundle against a white background.
For your additional images, you can either click Upload a New Image or Select Images that are already
on the product detail pages for your individual products.
Click the Save button to return to the new virtual bundle page with your images populated.
Finally, enter a full title, a short title, a price, a description, bullet points and an optional
SKU for your virtual bundle.
We recommend a brief descriptive bundle title that names the main product and additional products,
for example, Shampoo Plus Conditioner.
Your short title is what displays in spaces that are too small for your full title.
Try abbreviating your full title by eliminating accessory products or shortening words.
Remember that your price needs to be equal to or lower than the combined price for your products,
which we display to the right.
Your description and bullet points should be in the same format used on product detail pages for
individual products.
But make sure to highlight what's in your bundle.
Use complete sentences for the description and start each bullet with a short phrase that identifies
a value, followed by a fragment that offers additional information.
You don't have to enter a SKU for a bundle.
If you leave this field blank, we'll create one on your behalf, along with a unique asin for the
bundle.
But if you do enter a SKU, make sure it's unique.
Don't reuse a SKU from an individual product within the bundle or from any other part of your catalog.
After entering each piece of information for your bundle, click the Save and Publish button to create
it.
A new virtual bundle usually appears in the Amazon store within 24 hours.
It'll link to the individual products in your bundle.
And the product detail page for the main product may also link to your new virtual bundle from a
Make It a Bundle widget.
If you need to update an existing bundle, hover over Inventory in the main menu in Seller Central,
then click Manage All Inventory.
Locate the bundle, which will be listed with your other products, with bundle as its status.
You can update the price, title, description, bullet points, and images, but you won't be able to
update the products in the bundle, adjust the main product, or change the SKU.
If you need to update these attributes, delete your bundle, then recreate it using a different SKU,
or recreate it using the same SKU after 24 hours have passed.
This concludes our training on virtual bundles.
We encourage you to watch our Seller University video on the Brand Analytics Market Basket Analysis
Report if you'd like help determining which products in your brand catalog might make an effective
bundle.
Thank you, and happy selling in the Amazon Store!